<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on A-Ali</title>
    <link>https://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on A-Ali</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ayaan Ali </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the use of LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/latex/</guid>
      <description>What is LaTeX? LaTeX is a typesetting and document preparation system that provides a similar function to word processors like Google Docs or Microsoft Word. However, LaTeX differs from these applications in that the user writes in plain text.
Corollary: What is plain text? Plain text is text that contains only characters and spaces without any stylistic or structural formatting already compiled on the page. To put it bluntly, you&amp;rsquo;re essentially coding a google document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building this site</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/intro/</guid>
      <description>Hugo for Static Sites It took me several tries at learning React, JS, and WebGL before I landed on hugo. I realized all of those tools were insanely overkill for what I was trying to accomplish: a portfolio site for someone who does not care for front-end development. Hugo is basically Wix but for back-end programmers. I coded the entire site from my Mac terminal and launched it on GitHub pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://example.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: aa4688@columbia.edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/profile/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Ayaan Ali, and I am a B.A. candidate in mathematics and computer science at Columbia University. I grew up in Brooklyn, NY and chose to stay in the city for higher education. Academically, I&amp;rsquo;m mainly interested in the theory of computation, computational learning theory, and pure mathematics. Eventually, I hope to pursue a PhD in CS and conduct research full time. In my free time, I postulate a lot about media and film as well as data analysis and visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
