<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on A-Ali</title>
    <link>https://ayaan.wiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on A-Ali</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ayaan Ali </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ayaan.wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to take notes if you&#39;re lazy</title>
      <link>https://ayaan.wiki/posts/notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayaan.wiki/posts/notebook/</guid>
      <description>In high school, my notetaking system was all over the place. For some classes, I had detailed, comprehensive, and organized notes and flashcards that legitimately helped me with preparing for tests and quizzes. On the flipside, I had courses where I barely wrote two incoherent lines on a single page. Why was that?
It took me a long time to figure out that my notetaking system was highly dependent on how the instructor or teacher presented information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the use of LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://ayaan.wiki/posts/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayaan.wiki/posts/latex/</guid>
      <description>What is LaTeX? LaTeX is a typesetting and document preparation system that provides a similar function to word processors like Google Docs or Microsoft Word. However, LaTeX differs from these applications in that the user writes in plain text.
Corollary: What is plain text? Plain text is text that contains only characters and spaces without any stylistic or structural formatting already compiled on the page. To put it bluntly, you&amp;rsquo;re essentially coding a google document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building this site</title>
      <link>https://ayaan.wiki/posts/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayaan.wiki/posts/intro/</guid>
      <description>I developed this site using a tool called Hugo which is a static site generator written in the programming language Go. I am not skilled at front-end development in any way but also did not want to just use a random template and host on Wix or Squarespace. I used Hugo for a few reasons:
Speed: this is a blazing fast site. Near instantaneous transitions between pages. Free and Open-Source: goes without saying why this is a plus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ayaan.wiki/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayaan.wiki/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: aa4688@columbia.edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://ayaan.wiki/posts/profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayaan.wiki/posts/profile/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Ayaan Ali, and I am a B.A. candidate in mathematics and computer science at Columbia University. I grew up in Brooklyn, NY and chose to stay in the city for higher education. Academically, I&amp;rsquo;m mainly interested in the theory of computation, computational learning theory, and pure mathematics. Eventually, I hope to pursue a PhD in CS and conduct research full time. In my free time, I postulate a lot about media and film as well as data analysis and visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
